これは…
鈴羽…
あたしが タイムトラベラー
タイムマシン
あたしは 2036年から来たんだ
ジョン･タイターだよ
This is...
A time machine.
I'm from the year 2036.
Suzuha...
I am the time traveler
John Titor.
Missing Link Necrosis
2036年
世界はＳＥＲＮに支配されていた
The year 2036.
The world was ruled by SERN...
そこは 徹底した管理社会
ディストピア
An oppressive, totalitarian society, a dystopia.
人々は 自由を奪われ
死んだように暮らしてる
The people's freedom was stolen,
and they lived like zombies.
逆らう者は 皆 殺された
Anyone who disobeyed was killed.
あたしは
そんなＳＥＲＮの支配から
I was part of the resistance,
人々を解放するために戦う
レジスタンスの一員だった
fighting to free the world from SERN's control.
あっ… ううっ！
ふっ！
この死んだような世界を
変えるため
To change this dead world...
あたしは 父さんが残してくれた
タイムマシンに乗り込んだ
...I entered the time machine my father left me.
そうして 未来を変えるために
And to change the future.
では ＠チャンネルに
書き込んだことは すべて…
Then, everything you wrote on @channel...
うん ほとんどは真実
Yes, most of it was true.
だけど
ＳＥＲＮは 研究機関であって
But SERN is a research organization,
権力を持つ統治機関じゃないわ
not a ruling body.
私は 何度も ネット上で
On the net, I told John Titor that many times.
ジョン･タイターに
そう 訴えてきた
待て！ ということは お前…
Wait!
Does that mean you
あの時 ＠チャンネルにいた
｢栗悟飯｣と ｢カメハメ波｣か？
are Chestnut Rice and Kamehameha?
タイターの中の人が
名乗り出たんだから
Titor identified himself,
私も名乗り出ないと
フェアじゃないでしょ
so it wouldn't be fair not to identify myself, too...
はっ… ならば 俺も倣おう
Then I'll identify myself, as well.
俺は 鳳凰院 凶真という真名で…
I was using the handle Hououin Kyouma...
それは知ってる
あっ…
We know that.
ＳＥＲＮは
タイムマシンの開発に成功したの
SERN succeeded in developing a time machine.
時間という
４つ目の次元に干渉できる
By becoming the only ones able to
唯一の存在となったことで
世界の秩序を塗り替えた
interfere with the fourth dimension, time,
they remade the entire world map.
そして 牧瀬 紅莉栖は
And Makise Kurisu is the person
ＳＥＲＮのタイムマシン開発に
最も貢献した人物
who contributed the most to
the time machine's development.
タイムマシンの母として
あがめられている
She's worshipped as the
mother of the time machine.
私がＳＥＲＮに協力？
冗談じゃないわ！
I worked with SERN?
No way!
人体実験までするような連中に
なんで 私が…
Why would I work with the kind of people who
perform human experiments?
未来では そうなっていた
That's what happened in the future.
あっ…
So that's why you hated me...
それで 私のこと 目の敵に…
んっ…
ならば 未来の俺は？
Then, what about the future me?
岡部 倫太郎は
テロリストとして有名
Okabe Rintarou is a famous terrorist.
テロ？
Terrorist?
ＳＥＲＮに盾突いたテロリスト
A terrorist who fought SERN.
そして 君たちは…
And you're both...
２人とも 2036年には死亡している
dead in the year 2036.
あっ…
おっ…
もう行かないと
待て！
I need to hurry.
Wait.
そんな とんでもないことだけ
言い残して 未来へ帰るつもりか？
You're saying something crazy like that,
and returning to the future?
だから 行くの
そんな未来を変えるために過去へ
That's why I'm leaving.
I'm going to the past, to change that future.
1975年へ
To 1975...
えっ… 1975年？
1975?
ＳＥＲＮが
タイムマシン開発に成功したのは
SERN succeeded in developing the time machine,
2010年に 秋葉原でつくられた
タイムマシンがあったから
due to the time machine created
in 2010, in Akihabara.
電話レンジのこと？
うん
You mean the Phone Microwave?
ＳＥＲＮは
通信傍受システムを使って
SERN used a communications monitoring system
世界中から タイムマシンに関する
あらゆる情報を集めていた
to gather all the information they could
on time machines, from around the world.
そのシステムに 岡部 倫太郎
I think the first D-mail you sent tripped the system.
君が最初に送ったＤメールが
引っ掛かったんだと思う
ラジ館前で送った あのメールが…
The message I sent in front of the Radio Building?
そう だから ＳＥＲＮの
データベースに残っている
Yes.
So if we delete the message from SERN's database,
そのメールを消しさえすれば…
未来は変わる
the future will change.
あっ…
ＳＥＲＮが タイムマシンの開発に
成功しなかった
We can go to the beta world line, where SERN
β世界線へ行くことができる
never successfully created a time machine.
そうすれば まゆりも助かるのか？
Will that save Mayuri?
あっ… 多分
I think so.
だったら すぐにでも
Then we should start hacking
SERN's database immediately...
ＳＥＲＮのデータベースに
ハッキングをかけて…
それには IBN5100が必要
We need the IBN 5100 for that.
そうか それで…
I see. So that's why...
あたしの使命は 1975年に行って
My task was to go to 1975,
IBN5100を手に入れ
岡部 倫太郎に託すこと
find an IBN 5100,
and get it to Okabe Rintarou.
あっ…
But I stayed too long, looking for my father.
なのに 父さんを捜そうとして
この時代に長居しすぎた
もっと早く行くべきだったのに…
I should have gone earlier.
あっ！
あっ…
大丈夫？
Is everything okay?
そんな… 壊れてる
No...
It's broken.
あっ…
えっ？
マズい！
どうする？
This is bad!
What do we do?
俺が 何とかする
I'll think of something.
２人は隠れて 隙を見て逃げろ
You hide.
As soon as you can, run.
誰か いるのか？
Anyone here?
誰だ？
近づくな！
Who's there?
Stay back!
機関の謀略を阻止するための
作戦行動中だ！
I'm in the midst of an operation
to end the Organization's schemes!
これは
レベル17の極秘ミッションである
This is a level-70 top-secret mission.
分かったら 即刻 離れるがいい
こっちだ 急げぃ！
So stay away from this place!
This way! Hurry!
あっ こら！
あっ 待ちなさい！
Hey!
Wait!
逃げるわよ！
あっ…
We're running.
早く！
Hurry!
未来じゃ
どうだったか知らないけど
I don't know what happened in the future,
今の私は
あなたと同じ ラボメンなのよ！
but right now, I'm a lab member, just like you!
あっ…
うっ…！ はあ はあ…
岡部！
無事だったか
Okabe!
You're safe?
逃げるぞ！
Let's go!
どうする？
もう あそこには戻れないわよ
What do we do?
We can't go back there.
タイムマシンは壊れていたのか？
Was the time machine broken?
Was it from when it crashed into the roof?
屋上に衝突した衝撃で？
あれは 衝突したんじゃないよ
It didn't crash.
座標計算に誤差があったせいで
あの位置に出現しちゃっただけ
There was an error in calculating the coordinates,
where it appeared.
着いた時は壊れていなかった
When I arrived, it wasn't broken.
だったら いつ…？
Then when?
考えられるとすれば この前の雷雨
If I had to guess, I'd say that thunderstorm we had...
あっ…
It might have been hit by lightning, or flooded...
落雷したか
それとも 浸水したか…
俺のせいだ
あっ…？
It's my fault.
俺が あの夜 引き止めたせいで…
Because I stopped you then...
タイムリープマシンで…！
I'll use the time leap machine...
We can only use it to go back 48 hours.
それじゃあ 最大48時間までしか
さかのぼれない
あっ… あの夜までは届かない
We can't get back to that night.
ああ オカリン！
Okarin!
And Kurisu-chan and Suzu-san are with you!
紅莉栖ちゃんと鈴さんも一緒だ
お前たち
帰ったのではなかったのか？
You didn't go home?
まゆ氏が やっぱり
完成祝いするべきって言うから
Mayushii said we should have a party to celebrate
the time machine's completion.
ダル君と２人で
買い出しをしてきたのです！
Daru-kun and I went shopping!
今日は解散と言っただろ！
I said we were done for the day!
ごめんね まゆり
I'm sorry, Mayuri.
これから 私たち
重要な話をする予定だったの
We have to talk about something important.
オカリン？
Okarin?
とにかく
今日のところは帰ってくれ
Just go home for today.
完成祝いは また 改めて やろう
We'll have the party another time.
分かった…
All right.
でも 危ないことはしないでね
But don't do anything dangerous.
まゆしぃは心配なのです
Mayushii is worried.
大丈夫だ 約束する
It'll be fine.
I promise.
うん
それじゃあ また 明日！
See you tomorrow, then!
ああ
Yeah.
電車 止まってるって
マジか？
I heard the trains stopped.
Seriously?
あっ…！
タイムマシンを修理するしかない
We'll have to repair the time machine.
ウッフフ…
まず 今から５時間前
First, go back five hours ago,
つまり タイムリープマシンの
完成した時間まで跳ぶ
to when the time leap machine was completed.
From there, go back 48 hours.
そこから 改めて 48時間
To 2:00 PM, on the 11th.
11日の14時まで跳ぶ
それが 今の あたしたちが使える
最大の時間ってわけだね
That's the most time we have.
その２日の間に 何としてでも
タイムマシンを修理する
I'll finish the time machine during those two days,
no matter what.
できなければ
何度でも その２日をやり直す
If I can't, I'll redo those two days
as many times as it takes.
これは
世界を救うためなどではない
This isn't to save the world.
まゆりを助けるための
ミッションだ
It's a mission to save Mayuri.
はっ…！
岡部？
あっ…
Okabe?
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
至急 ラボメンに招集をかけてくれ
Gather all the lab members right away.
聞いてもらいたいことがある
There's something I want to talk to them about.
未来人 すげえ マジ パねぇっす
Future tech FTW.
This must be photoshopped.
直せるか？
Can you fix it?
阿万音氏 自分では無理なん？
Miss Amane, you can't do it yourself?
私には ちんぷんかんぷん
It's too much for me.
My father's the one who made it.
つくったのは 父さんだから
2036年のタイムマシンを
現代の技術で直せるわけ…
There's no way we can fix a time machine
from 2036, using today's technology.
やってみなければ分からん！
We won't know until we try.
Anyway, try and do it in two days, Daru.
とにかく
２日で 何とかしてくれ ダル
お前だけが頼りだ
You're our only hope.
Why two days?
なんで ２日なん？
あっ…
それは… とにかく ２日だ！
Well...
Just do it!
もし ２日で直せたら
何でも言うことを聞いてやる
If you can, I'll do anything you want.
Teacher, I want to have a
day-long date with Feyris-tan!
先生！ フェイリスたんと
一日デートがしたいです！
分かった 何とかしよう
いやあ 無理っしょ？
All right, I'll make it happen somehow.
No, that's impossible.
俺に 不可能はない！ 信じろ
I can do anything!
Believe in me.
んっ…
You're serious? For real?
マジ？ 絶対？
約束する
I promise.
だから やってくれ
So do it.
いいですとも！
Very well!
あっ… あと もう一つ いい？
ああっ…
One more thing, okay?
無事に直ったら IBN5100と一緒に
If I fix it, in addition to the IBN 5100,
1975年の伝説の魔法もの
get me a cel from the legendary
ラジカル少女 オミットちゃんの
セル画も持って帰ってきて…
1975 magical girl anime, Ragical Girl Omit-chan!
自重しろ！
Shut up.
私も手伝おうか？
いや お前には
Should I help, too?
No, you need to finish the time leap machine.
タイムリープマシンを
完成させるという
重要な仕事がある
そろそろ ラボに戻った方がいい
We should get back to the lab.
Hey, aren't you all forgetting something?
ねえ みんな
もう一つ 何か忘れてない？
鈴さんの お父さん捜し
Looking for Suzu-san's dad.
父さんのことは もういい…
よくないよ！
I'm all right...
No, you're not!
鈴さんが
タイムマシンに乗ったのは
You got in the time machine
使命とかもあるけど
because you had a job to do,
やっぱり お父さんに
会いたかったからなんでしょ？
but also because you wanted
to see your dad, right?
だったら まゆしいは
会わせてあげたいのです
So Mayushii wants to help you find him.
父親の名前は
バレル･タイターだったな？
Your dad's name was Barrel Titor, right?
それは コードネーム
本名は知らない
That was his code name.
I don't know his real name.
阿万音っていうのは？
母さんの名前
What's Amane?
My mom's name.
My only clue is this little badge he had.
手がかりは 父さんの形見の
このピンバッジだけ
お父さんは
2010年の秋葉原にいるんだよね？
Your dad is in 2010 Akihabara, right?
それじゃあ まゆしいは
早速 捜査を開始するのです！
Okay, Mayushii will be the investigator.
Shiina Mayuri... She's a good girl, isn't she?
椎名まゆり いい子だね
う～ん…
Think you can fix it?
直りそう？
No way to say for sure yet.
いや まだ 確証はないけど…
But when I looked at it, I realized...
ただ ちょっと触ってみて
気付いたんだけど
これって 電話レンジと似てるかも
It's kind of like the Phone Microwave.
Then it's possible you can fix it, right?
じゃあ
直る可能性はあるってことだね？
うん
ウフッ…
I wonder if your dad's nearby.
阿万音氏の おやじさんって
僕たちの近くにいるのかな？
2010年に
僕達が このアキバにいるって
He knew that we were in Akiba, in 2010, right?
知ってたんだよね？
I think so.
多分…
直接 聞いたわけじゃないから
But I never heard from him directly.
私 父さんには会ったことないし
I've never met him.
全部
父さんの遺書に書いてあったんだ
Everything was in his will.
父さんは ＳＥＲＮとは別に
タイムマシンの研究をしてたの
My dad was researching a time machine,
separately from SERN...
To change the future.
未来を変えるためにね
あたしは
その遺志を継いで ここにいる
I'm here to carry on, in his place.
I really am sorry...
正直 すまんかった
ああ でも タイムマシンが直れば
何とかなるって
But it might be that, if I can fix the time machine,
we'll find your dad before you get back from 1975.
1975年から戻ってくるまでに
おやじさん 捜しておくから
だから オカリンには ないしょで
伝説のアニメ ラジ…
So keep this a secret from Okarin,
and try to get me that cel...
随分と地道ね
That's a pretty straightforward way to do it.
仮にも
未来ガジェット研究所なんだから
Supposedly, we're the future gadget lab.
I guess you don't have a more futuristic way?
もっと未来的な方法はないの？
そんな都合のいいものはない
Nothing so convenient.
うんっ…
｢未来ガジェット２号
オルタナティヴ･エディション
Future Gadget #2, Alt. Edition,
バージョン 2.67｣
Version 2.67.
通称 ｢タケコプカメラー｣
AKA The Bamboo Copter Camera.
There's a CCD camera on the lower body.
ＣＣＤカメラが
本体下部に搭載されている
意外と まともそう
Surprisingly sane.
Could we use this for an aerial search?
これで
上空から捜すっていうのは？
The camera spins, too,
カメラも一緒に回るので
so the video you receive revolves at a high speed.
撮影された映像も
高速回転している
バージョン 2.67で
そんな不具合が直ってないの？
You're at version 2.67, and that still isn't fixed?
That's the first one we've made.
それが初号機だ
Daru came up with the name, along with the version.
ネーミングは
バージョンも含めて ダルの趣味で
There's no real meaning.
特に 意味はない
あっ…
ダルは？
まだ残って 作業を続けてる
Where's Daru?
He's still there, working.
うん？
The Divergence Meter...
ダイバージェンスメーター
やっぱり これは
You made it. I think you should have it.
作った本人である
君に預けておこうと思って
この数字が
１％を突破さえできたら
If this number goes above 1%,
the future will change.
未来は変わる
それを認識できるのは
You're the only one who will know,
運命探知の能力を持った君だけ
with your Reading Steiner.
未来の俺は 死ぬ前に
それをお前に託したのか？
Did I give you that, before I died in the future?
ううん
あたしは 一度も会ったことはない
No, I've never met you.
君はさ あたしが所属している
レジスタンスの
You were a founding member
of the resistance I was in.
設立メンバーだったんだよ
I founded a resistance?
レジスタンスの設立
フッ… くだらない
How stupid.
I couldn't even save Mayuri.
まゆりを助けることもできず
のうのうと生き続けた挙げ句
And I kept on living!
Acting like a stupid little kid, with his fantasies?
そんな厨二病みたいなマネを…
It wasn't stupid!
くだらなくない！
It was an honest, brave desire to save the world!
世界に自由を取り戻そうとする
勇敢で立派な志だよ
あっ…
ああ… ヘイ マスター
Hey, mister...
ううっ…
I am mad scientist!
アイアム マッドサイエンティスト
イッツ ア クール！
It's so cool!
サノバビッチ！
Sonuvabitch.
はい 何ですか？
Hi, what is it?
ああ… 日本語でおｋ か
So, Japanese works, huh?
There's something I want to ask you.
ちょっと聞きたいことがある
Ever seen this before?
これに 見覚えは？
I want to know where it came from.
これの出どころが知りたい
調べることはできないか？
Can you look into it for me?
オオ～ 思い出し…
The remember.
Sorry. It is difficult.
ソーリー ちょっと難しいですね
日本語 あんまり
ＯＫじゃないんじゃない？
You sure about that Japanese working?
ふう… 思い出したら
ここに連絡をくれ
If you remember, contact me here.
Maybe this will be created in the near future,
もしかして
近い未来に作られるもので
今は まだ存在しないんだろうか？
but doesn't exist now?
やっぱりさ
父さんとは会えない運命なのかも
I may be fated to not meet my dad, after all.
Want to give up on it?
もう やめにしない？
諦めるのか？
You're giving up?
まだ あと１日
残っているんだぞ！
We still have a day!
Why are you so mad—
なに 怒って…
俺だって！
I want to prioritize saving Mayuri!
まゆりを助けることを
なにより優先したい
Even so, you're a lab member and a friend.
それでも
お前は ラボメンであり仲間だ
I want to help you if I can!
その仲間が困っているんだから
助けたい！
それなのに
お前が真っ先に諦めて どうする！
So why are you already giving up?
D-Don't yell at me, okay?
ど どなんないでよ…
おっ…
ウフフ…
すまん
I'm sorry.
Please!
お願いしま～す お願いしま～す！
What is she...
あいつ 何を…
There was a kidnapping yesterday!
先日 誘拐事件が起きちゃいました
このピンバッジをつけた犯人を
捜してま～す！
I'm looking for the criminal.
He wore a badge like this!
ご協力 よろしくお願いしま～す！
Please help us!
うん？ おお オカリン！
Okarin!
Look! Look!
見て見て！
はあ… まゆり…
Mayuri...
エヘヘ… いい作戦でしょ
Good idea, right?
It was Mayushii's idea!
まゆしぃのアイディアなのです！
I think everyone might go, "Huh?"
when they see this.
これなら みんな おっ？って
思ってくれるかなあって
作戦名は
｢まゆしぃ チラシで大勝利｣！
This is operation:
Big Victory with Mayushii's Pamphlets!
I think a kidnapping is going too far, don't you?
誘拐事件ってのは
さすがに 言いすぎなんじゃ…
警察に目を付けられたら
どうする？ おおっ…
What if the police start looking at us...
Oh, no! Run!
マズい 逃げるぞ
えっ 何？
What?
Hey, you guys!
ちょっと 君たち！
こら 待ちなさい！
Wait!
うう… あっ あっ…
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
From now on, ask me about these operations first,
次からは 作戦名も含めて
事前に 俺に相談するんだな
including the name...
うっ！ ふっ ふっ…！
うん？
何やってんの？
What are you doing?
Oh, it's Christina.
なんだ クリスティーナか
Good timing.
ちょうど よかったわ
大変なことが分かったの
I learned something really bad.
What?
何だ？
When I went to buy lunch, I overheard the clerks.
お昼 買いに行ったら
店員が話してるのを
聞いちゃったんだけど…
Amane-san's dad might be a kidnapper.
阿万音さんの お父さん
誘拐犯かも…
あっ…
えっ？
ああ…
うん？ な… 何？
Wh-What?
どういうこと？
ウフフフ…
What's going on?
調子は？
うん？
How's it going?
Something to drink.
差し入れだ
If you were awesome, you would've brought me
ここは キンキンに冷えた
ノンカロリーのコーラだろ
an ice-cold zero-calorie cola.
常識的に考えて
Well?
どう？ タイムマシンは直りそう？
Can we fix the time machine?
Probably by tomorrow.
明日までには なんとか
Even working this whole time,
that's still amazing!
すごいね！ 突貫工事とはいえ
ダルの実力は 折り紙つきだ
Daru's the real thing.
見た目は 不摂生そうで
さえない感じなのにね
Even if he looks unhealthy and kind of dim.
Don't judge him by his looks.
見た目で判断するな
Yeah. I've changed my mind about him.
うん 考えを改める
Then you help me, too.
それじゃ 阿万音氏も手伝って
And then, in the steaming hot confines
of the time machine,
そして 狭いタイムマシンの中
うだるような暑さに
僕らは 恥ずかしさも忘れて
服を脱ぎ…
we can forget our shame
and take off our clothes...
あっ…
自重しろ HENTAI！
Shut up, pervert!
Daru-kun and Suzu-san look good together.
ダル君と鈴さんって
結構 お似合いだね
はあ？ お似合いか？
Together? How?
どのへんがだ？
I don't really know how to say it...
どのへんって言えないけど
なんとなく
Just, somehow.
うん？ どうしたの？
What's up?
Don't worry about it!
気にするな まゆりが
おかしなことを言っただけだ
Mayuri was just saying something weird.
But if the time machine gets fixed,
でも タイムマシンが直ったら
I'm worried about Suzu-san when she rides it!
乗っていっちゃう
鈴さんが心配だな
If it were for two, I could go with you...
２人乗りなら まゆしいが
一緒に行ってあげられるのに
Why would you go with her?
お前が一緒に行って
どうするのだ？
Why else?
決まってるよ 鈴さんの手を
ムギュ～っと握ってね
I'd hold Suzu-san's hand really tight, and I'd say,
"It's okay! Mayushii's with you, so it's okay!"
大丈夫 まゆしぃが一緒だから
大丈夫だよって応援してあげるの
ウフッ…
Hey, I'm saying this because
あのさ 今 言わないと
I don't think I'll ever have
the chance to say it again.
機会を 永遠に
逃しちゃいそうだから言うけど…
What? That's an exaggeration.
何だ？ 大げさだな
I'm really grateful to you all.
あたしさ 君たちには
ホント 感謝してるんだ
うん？
When I first came here, I didn't know anyone.
初めて この時代に来た時
知ってる人は誰もいなくて
Even though this era is much more peaceful,
この時代の方が
すごく平和なのにさ
somehow, to me, it was really scary.
なんだか あたしにとっては
すごく怖かった
でも 今は こうして
たくさんの仲間が出来た
But now I have lots of friends.
この時代に来ることができて
君たちと同じ時間が過ごせて
I'm really happy that I could come here...
あたし ホントに楽しかった
That I could spend time with you guys.
ほんのちょっとでも
ラボメンの一員になれてよかった
I'm glad I could be a lab member, just for a while.
君たちと一緒にいられて…
よかった
I'm glad I could spend time with you...
鈴羽…？
Suzuha...
岡部 倫太郎
きっと 未来を変えてね
Okabe Rintarou! Change the future...
Make it a free world, like this one!
今みたいな 自由な世界に変えて
Suzuha?
鈴羽…
あっ…
はい… うん？
Yes?
ハロー マッドサイエンティスト
ソー クール
Hello?
Mad scientist so cool?
あっ… 昼間の露天商か
The guy from this morning?
I remembered...
私 思い出しましたね
イエスタデー ナイト
ピンバッジの男
About that pin badge from yesterday.
You found her father?
父親が分かったということか？
あっ…
I'll be right there!
すぐに行く 待ってろ！
Wait!
イエ～ス そのゲストが
メイク ミー プリーズ ピンバッジ
ユーが持ってきたのと
セイムだった～のよ
その男が ピンバッジの制作を
依頼したんだな？
うん？
はあっ… はあっ…
そいつは どんな男だった？
どんな？ そうね…